https://www.pedaids.org/privacy-policy/

Skip to main content
Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation
We’ve seen incredible success in pediatric HIV and AIDS. But our work is not over. Join us in the fight for an AIDS-free generation.
Privacy Policy
The Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation (“EGPAF”) maintains this website (www.pedaids.org) in order to provide you with information about our work, programs, and events, as well as an online forum to interact with us. This Privacy and Cookies Notice describes EGPAF’s treatment of information that you provide through our website; it explains what information we collect, how it is protected, and how we use it.
Your use of this website constitutes your agreement to the terms and conditions of this policy.
Changes to the Privacy Policy
We reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time and without notice. Any and all changes will be posted on this page. We encourage you to check this page regularly. Your continued use of the website following any changes to this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such changes.
Cookies
The EGPAF website uses “cookies” – small text files that are stored in your computer’s browser to aid and simplify your use of our website. You may change your browser settings to not accept cookies or to periodically delete cookies from your browser. The cookie cannot capture your e-mail address, retrieve any data from your hard drive, or pass on a computer virus; it simply collects information you have entered into our website to simplify future visits.
Third-party cookies
Third-party analytics services
We use third-party analytics services, including Google Analytics and others, to collect information about your use of our sites and enable us to improve how our sites. You can learn about Google’s practices by going to https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners. Google Analytics and other third-party analytics services use cookies and similar technologies to collect information about use of our sites and to report website trends to us, without identifying individuals to us. We use this information to see the overall patterns of usage on our sites, help us record any difficulties you have with our sites, and tell us whether our communication efforts are effective.
Social media and video sites
If you choose to share our digital content with friends through social networks, such as Facebook and Twitter, or to watch a video posted to a third-party media site (such as YouTube), you may be sent cookies from these third-party websites. We do not control the setting of these cookies, so please check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and how to manage them.
Information We Collect
We collect only the personal information you voluntarily provide to us, or that is given to us by entities or third parties that have your permission to share your personal information, such as when affiliated entities provide us with their email lists that they are authorized to share. Personal information includes (but is not limited to) your name, mailing address, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit or debit card number.
In correspondence, we use clear GIFs (image files) in our HTML-based e-mails to let us know which e-mails have been opened and use bounce-back technologies for undeliverable e-mails. These assist us in managing correct e-mail addresses, as well as in determining what information is important to you as a reader.
Each time you visit our website, our server will record your server address, your domain name, your browser type, your platform, the date and time of your visit, and the titles of the pages you view. This information is collected to help us diagnose problems, evaluate traffic patterns, and enhance the site’s usability. For instance, the most commonly-used pages should be refreshed with information more often, and the most popular browsers should be included in our test procedures before deployment.
How We Use Your Information
EGPAF may use your personal information to do the following:
Process your donation to EGPAF
Send you newsletters and informational  emails
Contact you about our events
Improve our website
Gain your input through reader surveys
Assist in your advocacy for pediatric AIDS issues
Create additional communications and activities that further EGPAF’s mission
Manage our relationship with you as our donor
We may receive information from other websites in order to process your donation or to contact you regarding a request you have made. For example, we may receive information from other websites such as those that host auctions and/or process payments in connection with your request regarding event registration details, event tickets, purchases from an auction, or general EGPAF information.
By making a donation and/or purchase, you consent to us providing your financial information to our service providers and other third parties as we determine necessary to process the transaction, such as Internet payment processing services and/or credit card processing services.
When you make a donation and/or purchase, you have the option to provide consent to enroll your email address into our digital mailing list. Through this list you may receive information about the work of EGPAF, the impact of your donation, event invitations, and other organization updates.  If you do not wish to receive these mailings, you do not have to provide consent.  You also consent to having your contact information data stored within our donor database. We will not store your credit card information. You can also follow the instructions below in the “How to Unsubscribe and/or Remove Your Data” section.
EGPAF does not share your personal information for use by other companies except in the case where those companies are performing a service for us or where you have agreed to allow such sharing of your personal information. For instance, a direct mailing for an event would require us to share your address with our direct mail supplier. Similarly, a credit or debit card number would be shared with a credit card processing company. These companies may only use the shared information to provide the requested service unless you consent otherwise, and EGPAF will always ensure that these companies commit to complying with all data protection regulations.
In order to increase our base of support and keep our costs low, EGPAF occasionally shares our donor names with other carefully selected organizations or data providers. Donors who wish to have their names removed from the exchange list can contact us at donate@pedaids.org.
How to Unsubscribe and/or Remove Your Data
You can opt out at any time from receiving e-mail communications, mailers, or telephone contacts from EGPAF. To do so, please contact donate@pedaids.org. E-mail messages also will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of receiving e-mail messages, via the “unsubscribe” link in the email footer.
To request that your data be completely removed from our records, please contact donate@pedaids.org. Please note that this action will be GDPR compliant. Should you reach out to donate@pedaids.org, please identify your email request with the subject line “Data Removal Request.”  EGPAF will consequently unsubscribe you from communications and anonymize your constituent information in our databases.
You can also make either of these requests by contacting us via phone at 202-296-9165. Please request to speak with the Development Donor Services Coordinator. Please note that changes to your preferences may take up to a week to be effective.
Security
Protecting your information is of paramount importance to us and we have taken all appropriate measures to protect the personal information we process from any breaches. However, be advised that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Our website uses industry-standard SSL encryption on pages where you submit donor or payment information. Information that you submit is protected through data access security, and only authorized users can access data that you submit. Further, financial information is retained only for transaction processing [and then erased]. We do not store your credit card information on our systems; all transactions are completed on secure partner sites [located in the EU].
Other Disclosures
EGPAF may also disclose your information in response to court orders or subpoenas, or if we determine that it is necessary to do so to comply with applicable laws or to protect the interests or safety of EGPAF or other visitors to the Web site. If EGPAF is sold to or merges with another company, or declares bankruptcy, some or all of the information collected from you may be transferred to a third party as part of the transfer of assets. [Should such situation occur, we would of course inform you on the modalities of such transfer.]
Links
The website may contain links to other sites including, among others, those of advertisers and other third parties whose trademarks may appear on the website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of the sites to which we provide links. You should carefully review the privacy policies of any linked sites you access via the EGPAF website.
Minors
This website is not intended for use by children.
Contacting Us
If you have further questions regarding this Privacy Policy, or regarding the use of changes, additions, or deletions to your personal information collected through this website, please contact us and include your name, telephone number, e-mail address, and home address so that we may contact you. You may also use this contact information to opt-out of receiving future commercial e-mail, telephone and mail communications from EGPAF. We can be reached in the following ways:
Via e-mail: donate@pedaids.org
Via telephone (Washington, D.C. headquarters): 202-296-9165
Via postal mail: Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation, 1140 Connecticut Avenue N.W. (Suite 200), Washington, D.C. 20036
Effective Date
This Privacy Policy is effective as of August 5, 2020.
You May Also Be Interested In
Ethics and Accountability
Financial Information and Annual Reports
Contact Us
Join Our Fight
With your help, we can and WILL achieve an AIDS-free generation. Stay up-to-date on the progress we’re making toward ending HIV/AIDS in children.
Email
Zip Code
Opt In
Until no child has AIDS.
About
About Pediatric AIDS
What We Do
Our History: 30 Years of Impact
Elizabeth’s Story
Our Global Leadership
Board of Directors
Donors and Collaborators
Blog
Founded over 30 years ago, The Elizabeth Glaser Pediatric AIDS Foundation is committed to a comprehensive response to fighting HIV and AIDS through research, global advocacy, strengthening of local health care systems, and growing the capacity of governments and communities in the world’s most affected regions to respond to urgent needs. We’re driven to see a world where no other mother, child, or family is devastated by this disease.
Donate
Careers
Contracting Opportunities
Contact Us
Press Releases & Statements
Financial Information and Annual Reports
Ethics and Accountability
Privacy Policy
